#### Blanca MANCILLA

4265, rue Jean-Brillant Montréal (Québec) H3T 1P2, Canada +1.514.591.2007

Email: blancalmancilla@gmail.com
Blog: superspreadsheet.wordpress.com

github: github.com/bluciam

Academic Web: mancilla.web.cse.unsw.edu.au

Written, spoken: English, French, Spanish.

Other: German, B1 level currently in Goethe Institut.



### **Professional Profile**

I have +10 years of experience in Computer Science research and teaching, and almost two years in Web development. I want to capitalize my skills and knowledge working in a team to create unique products to shape the future, disseminate knowledge to empower communities, to work in core problems. I am always learning and experimenting with current technologies, attending MeetUps, reading and writing technical blogs, or on Twitter.

#### **Positions**

2013–now Consultant, Montreal, Canada (Web Developer and Technical Writer)

- · Back-end developer using TDD and Ruby on Rails in a team of three (on going).
- · From conception to deployment (in Heroku) as sole developer in Ruby on Rails of a web portal for a Montreal startup (testing stage).

https://evening-harbor-6988.herokuapp.com

· Design and front-end development using CSS and HTML of a static site.

http://vinka-creations.bitballoon.com

· Technical Writer: Rewrite developers' interviews as reports for tax rebate claims.

2004–2015 Faculty Member (in Computer Science), UNSW Australia, Sydney

- · Lecturer; theses supervisor, assessor and advisor.
- · Researcher, team member, documentation writer, software evaluator.
- · Assignment conception, specification, deployment and marking.
- · Course administrator, curriculum advisor and assessor.

2009–2012 Faculty Member, University of Technology, Sydney (UTS), Australia

· Lecturer; curriculum redesigner; specification writer.

1993–1995 **Student Assistant** (Remote Sensing), Laval University, Québec, Canada

1991–1992 **System administrator**, IBM AS/400, Electro-Alloys, NY, USA

## Computer skills snapshot

· **Web programming** in Ruby on Rails, testing, CSS and Bootstrap, HTML, hook up to third party services (S3 Amazon Web Services, MailChimp, databases, social media).

- · **Intermediate** in Python
- · **Beginner** in JavaScript, JQuery, Django.
- · Open source development tools, Linux, shell scripting, CLI, git, 上下X.
- **Teaching knowledge** in programming languages (C, Java, Haskell), geographical information systems applied to civil engineering, ArcGIS, human computer interaction, information systems, computer graphics.

#### Research Software

SuperSpreadSheet (S<sup>3</sup>), https://github.com/bluciam/superspreadsheet

The purpose of this project was to display contextual electronic documents using the experimental programming language TransLucid. The case study used was a multidimensional spreadsheet and the framework was based on gtkmm.

Anita Conti Mapping Server, https://github.com/bluciam/anita-jsp-2005

This multilingual, multiversion collaborative tool was developed using JSP and the in-house library intense. Development iterations followed a constant change of requirements and research discoveries. The prototype was the base for my PhD.

TransLucid Project, http://sourceforge.net/projects/translucid

The project consisted of developing the concepts of Cartesian Programming and TransLucid. My role in the team was to participate in the planning stage, and to design the documentation structure. I was also the first user and tester.

## **Education**

1999-2004	PhD, Computer Science, UNSW Australia, Sydney
1993-1995	MSc, Geomatic Sciences, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1989-1991	BSc, Computer Electronic Science, Iona College, NY, USA
1984-1988	BEng, Computer Systems Engineering (four of five years), Industrial University of Santander (UIS), Colombia

# **Conference and Workshops Organization**

2015	PyLadies MeetUp Montreal
	Presentation: Learn to love the command line (slides here)
	Workshop (in preparation): git and gihub for Pythonists
2001-2002	International Conference on Distributed Communities on the Web, DCW 2002
	Local Arrangements Chair: Webmaster; budget and conference manager.
2000-2002	Women in Computing, UNSW, Director and founder:
	Liaison between community stakeholders; conception of events.
2000-2003	Girls in Science and Technology Workshops (an Anita Borg initiative),
	Founder, organizer, host: HTML, lego mindstorms and iMovie workshops.

#### **Publications**, http://plaice.web.cse.unsw.edu.au/archive/BLM

Total	28	Books	1	<b>Book Chapters</b>	1
		Journal Articles	5	Theses	2
		Conference Articles	17	Compilations	2